# Taejun Moon

Rue du Chatelet 11. Biel/Bienne Switzerland





Biel/Bienne, Switzerland

04.2021 - 07.2022

## Personal Profile

Data Engineer/Scientist from South Korea living in Switzerland since 2020 (**Permit-B, Familienangehöriger**).

Software engineering experience of 4+ years in Python, Data Pipeline, Data Visualization Dashboard, and Cloud Infrastructure.

Worked and studied in multi cultural environment (Korea, Japan, USA and Switzerland).

Currently working as a Data Scientist along studying Master's in Data Science.

# Work Experience \_\_\_\_\_

RocheBasel, SwitzerlandData Scientist (Internship, 100%)10.2022 - Current

- Development of privacy and anonymization framework for health informatics data
- Python K-anonymity implementation

#### Bern University of Applied Science (Berner Fachhochschule)

Research Associate (60%)

- Data pipeline with Apache Airflow for privacy preserved federated machine learning
- Python API Library for patient record retrieval from EMR system
- Documentation for Innosuisse project milestone reporting

Collab AsiaSeoul, South KoreaData Engineer/Analyst (100%)12.2019 - 09.2020

- Data ETL pipeline from YouTube API (AWS Glue, Athena, Batch, Lambda, S3) 10+GB per day
- Data visualization dashboard using Plotly, Django & QuickSight to support sales manager
- Terraform & GitLab CI/CD to build and manage cloud infrastructure on AWS

**Tesla**Seoul, South Korea
Business Development Analyst (Internship, 100%)
04.2019 - 11.2019

- Data analysis on charging infrastructure data to estimate yearly electricity price
- Preprocessing 30,000+ unstructured addresses data using Google Map API to visualize on Tableau
- Electricity expenses automation pipeline with web scrapping using Python & Selenium

#### **Hana Institute of Technology**

Research Assistant (Internship, 100%)

- Converting time series data into image and predicting using CNN
- 100+GB csv data multi core processing on AWS EC2

Seoul, South Korea 10.2018 - 02.2019

DECEMBER 11, 2022

#### **Education**

#### **Lucerne University of Applied Sciences (Hochschule Luzern)**

Lucerne, Switzerland

MSc in Applied Information and Data Science

09.2021 - Current

- IBM Watson Chatbot Challenge: Chatbot for pension recommendation on IBM Cloud
- MindFire: Extract user and skill profiles from Github and classify skill proficiency (MongoDB, GraphQL, KNN clustering)
- Master Thesis (Roche): K-anonymization on health data
- · Courses:

Data Warehouse and Data Lake Systems Applied Machine Learning and Predictive Modeling Database Management for Data Scientists Modern Data Engineering Data Collection, Integration and Preprocessing Designing and Managing Data Science Projects

Sophia University Tokyo, Japan

BSc in Engineering and Applied Science

09.2012 - 09.2018

- Studies on engineering and applied science (Mechanical Engineering, Electrical Engineering, Informatics)
- Bachelor's Thesis/Project: Obstacle detection and recognition using deep learning in Artificial Intelligence Lab 🗷
- Presented at the International conference on Image, Video Processing and Artificial Intelligence (IVPAI 2018)
- 2 years of leave of absence due to military duty in South Korea (2014-2016)

## Skills\_\_\_\_\_

**Programming** Pandas, PySpark, Airflow, SQL, ETL, AWS, Pytorch, Tableau Python, Javascript, CI/CD, Git, Linux, Docker, Jira

## Activities\_\_\_\_\_

2022	<b>Energy Data Hackdays</b> , Energy (Heat Demand) modelling in Sankt Gallen with AI methods	Brugg, Switzerland
2022	IBM Watson Chatbot Challenge, Pension fund recommender chatbot	Online, Switzerland
2021	Sports Hackdays, XC Battery Model	Lucerne, Switzerland
2021	MindFire, Autonomously extracting user and skill profiles	Switzerland
2018	<b>Spotify Sequential Skip Prediction Challenge</b> , Predict if users will skip or listen to the music	Online
2018	NIPS 2018: Adversarial Vision Challenge, Untargeted Attack Track	Online
2018	IVPAI 2018, Obstacle detection and recognition using SSD	Shanghai, China

# **Languages**.

English Professional proficiencyKorean Native proficiencyJapanese Professional proficiencyFrench Conversational proficiency

DECEMBER 11, 2022 2